(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-15T00:01:02.877361",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
刮目せよ
Feast your eyes!
この後 ラプラスさんの生誕祭があるらしいんですけど...
Apparently Laplus's Birthday Live is coming up next...
(ラプラスの生誕祭は)割とレベルの高い合格点を超える生誕祭をオールウェイズ出してくれる
(Laplus's Birthday Live) always delivers a performance that easily surpasses a high standard.
どこから来たんですか？
Where did you come from?
スト6の方から...
From the Street Fighter 6 community...
開会してるんでしょ？ / 閉会しています！
It's open, right? / It's closed!
開会してるって言ったじゃん！ / 閉会しています！
You said it was open! / It's closed!
ラプラス・ダークネスの生誕祭は... 閉会しています！
Laplus Darknesss's Birthday Live is... CLOSED!
みんなー！ 我輩の誕生日ライブに来てくれてありがとねー！
Everyone! Thank you for coming to my birthday live stream!
まずは1曲目！ 夜行性ハイズ！ 行くぞー！
First up, the first song: "Night Owl Highs"! Let's go!
正直体を忘れてたい
Honestly, I want to forget my body,
そんな顔でいつまで戦うの
How long will you fight with that face?
また一人で
Alone once again.
愛しても愛しても その度に傷つきが顔を出す
No matter how much I love, each time, hurt rears its head,
巻き戻すように
as if rewinding.
どうして力尽くまで さらに100まで 飲み込む悲しみだけは なくなってくれないの
Why is it that, until I'm exhausted, beyond 100%, the sadness I swallow just won't go away?
そうして逃げ場もないのに マイナス100から始まる動機の日々も 束の間
And so, with nowhere to run, those days driven from minus 100 are so brief...
忘れないや
I won't forget it
ちゃんと泣いて無理もしのいだら ここへおいでよ いつだって
Once you've had a good cry and gotten through it, come here anytime
これからを分かち合おうか
Shall we share what comes next?
眠たいが寝れないまだ境界 僕らだけの勝手思いやって 威張ってたって出ないよ
Sleepy but can't sleep, still on the border, showing our own selfish consideration, puffing our chests won't help
消せない海底は理想から なんかハイなハイが丁度いいや 作っていたいのか
The indelible seabed from ideals, a certain high vibe feels just right, do you wanna keep making it?
死にたい 消えたいもう異常じゃない？ よしよしの一手ですみ premium ほら吐き出しちゃおう
"I wanna die, I wanna disappear", isn't that abnormal? A soothing move to finish it, premium, come on, spit it out
君は泣いたって綺麗だよ さらば安心 留まり迷い 向いて笑ってこうじゃない
You're beautiful even when crying, farewell peace of mind, lingering in doubt, let's turn around and smile
寂しくない 悲しくない 無理重ねた強がりに 深いやお 洗い流せたら
"I'm not lonely, I'm not sad", if I could wash away the deep wounds behind my forced bravado...
バイバイお バイバイお バカみたいな世界にありがとう 探さないでね
Bye-bye, bye-bye, thank you to this foolish world, please don't look for me
そして僕らは広くも狭くも暑くも寒くもないこの部屋で 抱き合って息をするの
And so, in this room that's neither wide nor narrow, hot nor cold, we hug and breathe
常識外れを外れて2人だけの合言葉で鍵をかけたら さあどんな夜にしようか
Stepping past the unconventional, locking the door with our secret password, now, what kind of night shall we make it?
だけど痛い だから痛い 優しさが染み込んでいく 焦燥を始めようか
But it hurts, so it hurts, tenderness seeps in, shall we begin the impatience?
眠たいが寝れないまだ境界 声を何度だって遠くにやって 保ってきたが
Sleepy but can't sleep, still on the border, sending my voice far away again and again, holding on...
やめよう 逃げよう 大丈夫だよ もう寝たっていいの ちゃんと僕が守ってあげるから
Let's stop, let's run away, it's okay, you can sleep now, because I'll protect you proper
おはようしよう また今日にしよう よしよしの一手ですみ premium ほら吐き出しちゃおう
Let me say good morning, let's make it today again, a soothing move to finish it, premium, come on, spit it out
僕も泣いちゃってヤバいから さらばちびっと前を向いて笑ってこうじゃない
I'm crying too, it's crazy, farewell, let's face forward just a bit and smile, shall we?
弱虫な僕たちは 変わっていく
Cowardly as we are, we are changing
終わらない今日もハイで 光っていく 光っていく
Never-ending, today too, riding high, shining on, shining on
辛いのは嫌だけど 2人で乗り越えるさ
I hate painful things, but the two of us will overcome them
ありがとう！
Thank you!
えっとね、まだまだ続くから、めちゃくちゃ楽しんでってね！
Um, there's still plenty more to come, so have a ton of fun, okay?
バイバイ、バイバイ！
Bye-bye, bye-bye!
今回、ラプラスさんの生誕祭があるらしいんですけど...
Apparently, Laplus-san has a birthday stream event this time...
え、マジですか！？ あの、ラプラスさんってあのホロライブの！？
Wait, really?! That Laplus-san from Hololive?!
僕、あのーアレ、待ち受けにしてるんですよ！
I... um... I have her as my phone wallpaper!
しかも、今回の配信ハッシュタグが #ラプラス・バースデイ2025 らしっくて...
Plus, the stream hashtag this time is supposed to be #LaplusBirthday2025...
えー！マジでショックです！...でも幸せならOKです！
What! I'm seriously shocked! ...But if she's happy, then it's OK!
ねぇ私のことが好きなら 気付いて 気付いて 気付いて 気付いて 夢を見せてよ
Hey, if you love me, notice me, notice me, notice me, notice me, show me a dream
どうして分かってくれないの 嫌いだ 嫌いだ 嫌いだ 嫌いだ 二度と触れないで
Why don't you understand? I hate you, I hate you, I hate you, I hate you, don't ever touch me again
ちょっと待ってどこからおかしくなったの ダメなとこも好きになれて良かったのに
Hold on, where did things go wrong? I thought it was great that I could love even your flaws
服を脱いで誰かに埋めてもらえたら あなたのこと忘れられると思っていた
I thought if I shed my clothes and let someone fill the void, I'd be able to forget about you
気持ち切って傷ついて酷く泣いたけど 繋がってるなら悪くはないね
Cut my feelings and got hurt, crying terribly, but if we're connected, maybe it's not so bad
騙した 騙しい息生きてあやまって 優しくされると余計に辛いけど
Deceived, soul breathing, apologizing, being treated gently only makes it harder, but...
私だけでいいって信じちゃって
Believing that I was the only one for you...
バカだ
How stupid.
ねぇ私のことが好きなら 気付いて 気付いて 気付いて 気付いて 夢を見せてよ
Hey, if you love me, notice me, notice me, notice me, notice me, show me a dream
どうして分かってくれないの 嫌いだ 嫌いだ 嫌いだ 嫌いだ 二度と触れないで
Why don't you understand? I hate you, I hate you, I hate you, I hate you, don't ever touch me again
一二の三で 流れ星 あの子の...
One, two, three, a shooting star, that girl's...
呪ってあげるわ
I'll put a curse on you.
ねぇ明日あたしの体を返してよ
Hey, give me back my body tomorrow.
嘘つき 嘘つき 嘘つき 嘘つき 手の鳴る方へ
Liar, liar, liar, liar, follow the sound of clapping hands.
逃げ出す気だよ
You're planning to run away.
吸って吐いて そうちゃんと生きて
Inhale, exhale, that's right, live properly.
細小舐める愛のコードだとか 躾ける煙るそう
Licking the subtle chord of love, taming the haze.
ねぇ置いていかないで
Hey, don't leave me behind.
ねぇお腹が空いたの 見て見ぬふり 唾を吐いて
Hey, I'm hungry. Pretending not to see, spitting.
燃えないゴミにするんだ
Treating it as non-burnable trash.
なんで なんで なんで なんで なんで
Why? Why? Why? Why? Why?
ねぇ私のことが好きなら 気づいて 気づいて 気づいて 気づいて 夢を見せてよ
Hey, if you love me, notice me, notice me, notice me, notice me, show me a dream!
どうして解かってくれないの 嫌いだ 嫌いだ 嫌いだ 嫌いだ 大嫌いだ
Why don't you understand? I hate you, I hate you, I hate you, I hate you, I hate you so much!
もうあなたは逃げられないよ
You can't escape anymore.
気づいてる 気づいてる 気づいてる 気づいてる
I know it, I know it, I know it, I know it.
勝手に私はどうして罰が変われないの
Even so, why can't my punishment change?
死したいよ 死したいよ 死したいよ 死したいよ 離れたくないよ
I want to die, I want to die, I want to die, I want to die, I don't want to leave!
1 2 3で
On 1, 2, 3...
流れ星 あの子のこと 言ってあげるわ
Shooting star, I'll tell you about that girl.
ねぇ 最後にぎゅっとさせてほしい
Hey, hold me tight one last time.
ありがとう ありがとう ありがとう ありがとう
Thank you, thank you, thank you, thank you.
これであなたも...
With this, you too...
「次のラプラスさんの曲 アンドロイドガールらしいんですけど...」
"Word is Laplus's next song is 'Android Girl'..."
「えー何ですか？」
"Huh? What?"
「それは許せないと思います これ」
"I don't think that can be forgiven."
「『テメぇらバカかよ！』というのが第一ですね」
"First thought is, 'Are you guys idiots?'"
「ラプラスといえば、『アイドル』みたいなもの」
"When it comes to Laplus, she's like an idol."
「それはちょっとね 世間は許してくれませんよ」
"That's a bit... society won't stand for it."
妄想生来のつくりましょ 君と合致あうの勝手
Let's fabricate a delusion from birth, matching with you as we please.
かまってもっと足りないの 期待 思い出し満たし 嫉妬のスタイル
Pay attention to me, it's not enough! Expectations filling memories, jealous style.
変わる 変わる 傷つけ合っては持たないって
Changing, changing, saying hurting each other won't last.
嘘で仲直りごっこ 勘違いの騙し合い
Playing make-up with lies, mutual deception born of misunderstanding.
目を見ればすぐに分かるって バカみたい
Saying you can tell right away if you look into my eyes—how foolish.
妄想にしっくり来るほど
So well fitted to my delusion...
この愛は腐ってるんだよ
That this love is completely rotten.
早く気付いてくれよ
Realize it quickly!
アンドロイドガール おかしくなっちゃった
Android Girl, I've gone crazy.
僕だけのものになった君は誰なの
Who are you, who became mine alone?
ずっと ずっと信じてきたのにな
Even though I believed in you all this time...
アンドロイドガール 思い出話だけ
Android Girl, just talking about memories.
君とのキスが痛くて息を閉じたの
Kissing you hurt so much that I held my breath.
ずっと ずっと何度の愛を再起動したって
Always, always, no matter how many times I reboot love...
ちょっとだって変われなどしないよ
It won't change even a little bit!
あーかわいいね どうしてくれよ
Ah, so cute, what are you going to do about it?
もう疲れた ドキドキさせる罪でリサイズ
I'm already tired. Resizing under the crime of making my heart flutter.
うざい うざい の兵器商材 期待しているか分からないんだよ
Annoying, annoying armaments, I don't even know what I'm expecting.
エンドロールはまだですか どこに行っても一緒だなってマジで言いたいの
Is the end roll not here yet? I really want to say it's the same wherever we go.
感傷に浸っていたいから
Because I want to wallow in sentimentality.
あの頃を願っていたから
Because I was wishing for those days...
アリカタ教えてよ
Teach me how to be!
アンドロイドガール おかしくなっちゃった
Android Girl, I've gone crazy.
君だけのものになった僕が好きなの？
Do you like the me that became yours alone?
ずっと ずっと騙してきたんだね
You've been deceiving me all this time, haven't you?
アンドロイドガール 思い出話だけ
Android Girl, just talking about memories.
錆びついた腕で何度も僕を求めた
You sought me over and over with rusted arms.
ずっと ずっと何度の愛を再起動したって
Always, always, no matter how many times I reboot love...
ちょっとだって変われなどしないよ
It won't change even a little bit!
アンドロイドガール おかしくなっちゃった
Android Girl, I've gone crazy.
僕だけのものになった君は誰なの
Who are you, who became mine alone?
ずっと ずっと信じてきたのにな
Even though I believed in you all this time...
アンドロイドガール 思い出話だけ
Android Girl, just talking about memories.
君とのキスが痛くて息を閉じたの
Kissing you hurt so much that I held my breath.
ずっと ずっとお邪魔虫は離れない
Always, always, the nuisance won't leave.
君だけは許さない
I will never forgive you!
アンドロイドガール おかしくなっちゃった
Android Girl, I've gone crazy.
君だけのものになった僕が好き？
Are you in love with the me that became yours alone?
ずっと
Always,
ずっと騙してきたツケで
as payment for constantly deceiving you,
アンドロイドガール 重い病気なんだっけ
Android Girl, is it a serious illness?
錆びついた腕で何度も僕を求めた
With rusted arms, you sought me time and again.
ずっと
Always,
もっと何度も愛を再起動したって
even if I reboot love over and over,
ちょっとだって傷は癒えないのさ
the wound won't heal even a little bit.
ああ 愛を再起動したって
Ah, even if I reboot love,
ちょっとだって癒えないのさ
it won't heal even a little bit.
ホロライブでラプラスさんの影が薄いというお話なんですが…
People say Laplus-san has a faint presence in Hololive...
いや、納得できないね
No way, I can't accept that.
Q. ラプラスさんの魅力は？
Q. What is Laplus-san's charm?
ないんだな、それが！
That's the thing, she doesn't have any!
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー
Dear Doppelganger
どうもこんにちは君の分身です
Hello there, I am your alter ego.
何の冗談か目を擦ってみる
Wondering if it's a joke, I rub my eyes,
影が二つあって そしてまた伸びてゆく
and see two shadows, which then keep stretching.
「もう一人自分がいたら」って言いました
You said, "If only there were another me."
そんな真摯な願いが僕を呼んだのさ
Such an earnest wish summoned me.
そりゃ願ったとも 悲しきすべてのAGE
Sure I wished for it, all sad AGES.
家事はいいから折半してください 意味のない無意義な代償
Skip household chores and split things up, a meaningless and useless price to pay.
ねえ こんなことより大事なことがあるんだよ いいだろ？
Hey, there's something more important than this, alright?
えー やりますやります何でもやります 僕が君の分身です
Yes, I'll do it, I'll do anything! I am your alter ego!
罪は洗いで メサイアは言う
Wash away the sins, says the Messiah.
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 君は 君は誰？
Dear Doppelganger, who are you, who are you?
ああ 困惑交差して 僕は誰？
Ah, in intersecting confusion, who am I?
ねえ 譲り合っちゃいないけれど 証明の証拠なんて無いんだよ
Hey, though we aren't conceding, there's no proof of identity.
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 誰が 誰が君？
Dear Doppelganger, who is, who is the real you?
無知が生まれた存在に 誓った傷が拭えない
An existence born from ignorance, unable to wipe away sworn wounds.
鳴りやまない 覚めやまない 奇跡の輪廻が狂い出した世界を 染め上げてる パパ
Unceasing, unrelenting, painting over a world where the cycle of miracles went mad, Papa.
どうも様子がおかしいです曜日
Things seem somehow strange on this day of the week,
ひとつずつ崩れてゆく辻褄が
as logical consistency falls apart one piece at a time,
僕の賽を振る
rolling my dice.
お前は一体誰だと
"Who on earth are you?"
ちょっと待って知らない 知の知りもしない言葉
Hold on, I don't know that, words I've never heard of.
どうやっていつの間にあら影は遠ざけてゆく
How and when did my shadow start moving away?
僕は何なんだろう ねえどうか存在を返して
What am I? Hey, please give me back my existence.
あいにく様だが決定権はこちらで 道具は心地良くて
Unfortunately for you, I have the decision-making power, and being a tool feels good.
もうあなたの居場所がここにはないこと分かってるんでしょ
You already know there's no place for you here anymore, right?
ねえ 奪われたなら奪い返せばいいだろ 今度はお前の番だから
Hey, if it was stolen from you, just steal it back. It's your turn now.
罪は洗いで インベーダーは言う
Wash away the sins, says the Invader.
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 君は 君は誰？
Dear Doppelganger, who are you, who are you?
ああ 困惑交差して 僕は誰？
Ah, in intersecting confusion, who am I?
まあ それ相応の覚悟だよな 命の偽り出尽くすだけ
Well, that requires a suitable resolve, just using up all fake lives.
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 誰が 誰が君？
Dear Doppelganger, who is, who is the real you?
この世に折った二つ目 乾き果てる前に
Before the second shadow broken in this world completely dries up,
誰でもいい何でもいい 普通を頂戴 狂った世界が染め上げてる パパ
Anyone is fine, anything is fine, give me normalcy. The crazy world is painting over, Papa.
それはずっと続く人の暴走レース
It's a runaway human race that goes on forever,
火種あって殺し合っているのさ 軽く
sparks flying as they kill each other lightly.
欠けた昔の希望をまた安易に
Easily entrusting past chipped hope to each other once again,
託し合って生まれ変わる意思詠唱
chanting intent to be reborn.
僕の方がちゃんと君を生きられるから
Because I can live your life properly better than you,
君も次の誰かちゃんと奪わなくちゃ
you must properly steal from someone next too.
もう分かってんなら何をすればいいかさ
If you already know what you should do,
どうぞ誰か僕に奇跡をくれ
please, somebody give me a miracle.
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 君は 君は誰？
Dear Doppelganger, who are you, who are you?
ああ 困惑交差して 僕は誰？
Ah, in intersecting confusion, who am I?
もう 止まらない 戻れない とうに
It won't stop anymore, I can long no longer turn back.
こんにちは君の
Hello there, your...
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー それは それは僕
Dear Doppelganger, that is, that is me.
無知が生まれた存在に 絶望が傷痕が
In an existence born from ignorance, despair and scars...
もう鳴りやまない 冷めやまない 奇跡の輪廻が狂い出した世界を 染め上げるさ
Unceasing, unrelenting, I will paint over a world where the cycle of miracles went mad.
上手くやれよ ルンパッパ
Do it well, Roomba-ppa!
どうもこんにちは 君の僕です
Hello there! I'm your servant.
わー！
Wah!
紗痲
[Shama]
横しままとう 囚人ファムファタール
A femme fatale prisoner draped in corruption,
嘘もぞ絞りジュースをあおるような
gulping down juice squeezed from lies.
夜な夜な火遊びで一死する 常時の呪いが解ける頃
Dying once in night after night of playing with fire, just as the usual curse lifts,
違和感が残業している 空々寂々している
an uncanny feeling works overtime, desolate and empty.
淡々とさ 頭垂れた末に
Matter-of-factly, after hanging my head,
はい論破って
"Yes, refuted,"
乾坤一擲 サレンダー
a desperate surrender.
御利口 離合 利己的に
Clever, drifting apart, selfishly.
ポジ寄り願いを叶えたら
If I grant a positive-leaning wish...
笑うな愛を愛と呼ぶんなら
Don't laugh, if you're gonna call love "love,"
いかんせん僕はフールみたい
unfortunately, I look like a fool.
話したいこともないっていうから
Since you say you have nothing to talk about,
そこでご執心だと気づいたの
that's when I realized your obsession.
笑うな君を口説いていたんなら
Don't laugh, if I was trying to seduce you,
僕の達成度はどこへやら
where on earth did my progress go?
じれったい針とファンデーション
Tantalizing needles and foundation,
舌を晒せば騙されている
sticking out your tongue means you're being tricked.
横しままとう 囚人ファムファタール
A femme fatale prisoner draped in corruption,
嘘もぞ絞りジュースをあおるような
gulping down juice squeezed from lies.
夜な夜な火遊びで一死する 常時の呪いが解ける頃
Dying once in night after night of playing with fire, just as the usual curse lifts,
店頭天秤はおつむが軽い方に軍配を上げた
the shop scales ruled in favor of the lighter head.
出来損ないのくせに足も持ってない 絶世血結晶のように溺れたか
A failure who doesn't even have legs—did you drown like peerless blood crystals?
笑うな愛を愛と呼ぶんなら
Don't laugh, if you're gonna call love "love,"
いかんせん僕はフールみたい
unfortunately, I look like a fool.
話したいわけがないっていうけれど
You say there's no way you want to talk,
気づかないわけもないだろうな
but surely you can't fail to notice.
わざと僕の存在理由は
Purposely, the reason for my existence...
さわやか向きなアイロニーへ
to a refreshingly directed irony.
ブランデー肌に吸ったら
Soaking brandy into my skin,
しどろもどろになって戯れて
getting all flustered and fooling around.
ヴォーオ オーオ オーオ...
Woah-oh-oh-oh-oh...
笑うな愛を愛と呼ぶんなら
Don't laugh, if you're gonna call love "love,"
いかんせん僕はフールみたい
unfortunately, I look like a fool.
話したいこともないっていうから
Since you say you have nothing to talk about,
そこでご執心だと気づいたの
that's when I realized your obsession.
笑うな愛を愛と呼ぶんなら
Don't laugh, if you're gonna call love "love,"
いかんせん僕が居るみたい
unfortunately, it seems like I'm here.
終わりのキスも何杯目
Which drink is this ending kiss?
横しま見せかけ重ねて丸めている
Piling up corrupt pretenses and curling them up.
丸めているさ
Curling them up.
ヴォーオ オーオ オーオ...
Woah-oh-oh-oh-oh...
たくよ、スタジオ寒すぎんだよ！
Good grief, the studio is way too cold!
ちょっと... 寒すぎんだよ、この... このスタジオ、カバーのスタジオは...
I mean... It's way too cold. This... COVER's studio is...
えっ？
Huh?
たく... 意味がわからない。
Sheesh... I don't get it.
ふざけやがって...
Are you freaking kidding me...
たく...
Good grief...
椅子が冷たーい...
The seats are so cold...
てめぇか？
Is it you?
てめぇかよ？
It's you, isn't it?
えー、その腐った根性。
Ugh, with that rotten attitude.
笑ったね？
You laughed, didn't you?
その心笑ってるね？
In your heart, you're laughing, aren't you?
悪いけどね、あんたよりよっぽど生きてるんだよ！
I hate to break it to you, but I'm way more alive than you are!
吾輩は...
I am...
もっと生きてんだよ！
I'm way more alive than this!
おい
Hey,
最後までちゃんと見るって言って...
you said you'd watch till the end...
配信最後までちゃんと見るって言った！
You said you'd watch the stream till the end!
あー！
Aaargh!
僕がずっと前から思ってることを話そうか
Shall I tell you what I've been thinking for a long time?
友達に戻れたらこれ以上はもう望まないさ
If we could go back to being friends, I wouldn't ask for anything more.
君がそれでいいなら僕だってそれで構わないさ
If you're fine with that, then I don't mind either.
嘘つきの僕が吐いた反対言葉の愛の歌
An opposition-word love song spat out by a liar like me.
『天ノ弱』
[Song: Amanojaku]
今日はちょっとの差で気持ちは土砂降りの雨で天天気でした
Today, by a hair, my feelings were a downpour under clear skies.
昨日もずっと暇で一日中忙しくしてました
Yesterday too, I was free all day, keeping busy all day long.
別に君のことなんて考えてなんかいないさ
It's not like I'm thinking about you or anything.
いやでもちょっと本当は考えてたかもなんて
Well, but maybe I actually was thinking a little bit...
メリーゴーランドみたいに回る
Spinning like a merry-go-round,
僕の頭の中はもうグルグルさ
inside my head is already going round and round.
この両手からこぼれそうなほど
So much that it seems to spill from these hands,
君にもらった愛はどこに捨てよう？
where should I throw away the love you gave me?
限りのある消耗品なんて僕はいらないよ
I don't need consumables with a finite limit.
僕がずっと前から思ってることを話そうか
Shall I tell you what I've been thinking for a long time?
姿は見えないのに言葉だけ見えちゃってるんだ
Even though I can't see your form, only your words are visible.
僕が知らないことがあるだけで気が狂いそうだ
Just having things I don't know makes me feel like going crazy.
ぶら下がった感情がキレイなのか汚いのか
Whether these hanging emotions are beautiful or dirty,
僕にはまだ分からない独り占めするのはもう嫌なんだ
I still don't know, I'm tired of keeping it all to myself.
捨てるあてもないんだ
And I have nowhere to throw it away.
言葉の裏の裏が見えるまで待つからさ
I'll wait until I can see behind the back of the words,
待つくらいならいいじゃないか
so waiting shouldn't be so bad, right?
進む君と止まった僕の
Between you moving forward and me stopped,
縮まらない隙を何で埋めよう？
what should I fill this unclosable gap with?
まだ素直に言葉にできない僕は
I, who still can't put it into honest words,
天性の弱虫さ
am a natural-born coward.
この両手からこぼれそうなほど
So much that it seems to spill from these hands,
君に渡す愛を誰に譲ろう？
to whom should I give the love meant for you?
そんなの誰にも当てる宛があるわけないだろ
There's no way anyone else could be the intended recipient!
まだ待つよ
I'll still wait...
もういいよ
That's enough already...
もう離さない
I won't let go anymore
君のすべてさ
You are my everything
Be my baby
ノリユキさんが歌ってる！
Noriyuki-san is singing!
もう離さない
I won't let go anymore
君のすべてさ
You are my everything
Be my baby
『気まぐれメルシィ』
[Song: Kimagure Mercy]
ほらほらまた始まった
Look, look, it's starting again
得意の自己弁護言い訳
Your specialty self-defense excuses
でもね... だって...
But you know... Because...
ほらほらまた始まった
Look, look, it's starting again
ごめんからのキスのパターンって
The pattern of "I'm sorry" followed by a kiss
感じ... 安易...
Feels... so easy...
いつか私だけそんな夢見たこともあったけど
I once had that dream of being the only one for you, but...
寂しい時だけ電話してもううんざりだわ
Calling me only when you're lonely, I'm sick of it already!
全然私に興味ないじゃん 君が好きなのは自分でしょう
You're not interested in me at all, are you? The one you love is yourself!
やっぱり私に興味ないじゃん その話もう聞き飽きたわ
As I thought, you're not interested in me at all. I'm sick of hearing that story!
そもそも大体私に興味ないじゃん そうやってまたごまかして
In the first place, you're just not into me, covering it up like that again!
Oh be my boy わがまますぎる baby
Oh be my boy, you're way too selfish baby
抱きしめてよ
Hold me tight!
本当気休めはしょうがないな 甘やかしちゃしょうがないな 泣いたっていかないでっていったって変わらないよ
Can't help these empty comforts, can't help pampering you. Even if I cry or say "don't go", nothing changes!
もう少しだけならまあ踊ってもいいかもな とろけて溶けていきたいの
Just a little longer, maybe I can dance with you. I want to melt and dissolve away...
どんなアピールも意味ないし 気づいてくれないけど
No matter how I appeal to you, it's meaningless, and you don't even notice, but...
私があ寂しい時だって 会いにきて
Even when I'm feeling lonely, come see me!
全然私に興味ないじゃん どこがダメなのか教えてよ
You're not interested in me at all, are you? Tell me what's wrong with me!
やっぱり私に興味ないじゃん 携帯ばかりいじってさ
As I thought, you're not interested in me at all, just playing on your phone!
そもそも大体私に興味ないじゃん 少しくらい期待させて
In the first place, you're just not into me, at least let me hope a little!
Oh lonely girl 独り占めさせよ baby
Oh lonely girl, let me have you all to myself baby!
振り回さないで
Don't lead me around!
ねぇ maybe melody 1 2 3 Shall we dance 踊りましょう
Hey maybe melody, 1, 2, 3, shall we dance? Let's dance!
早く手と手つないで 最後にひとつだけ
Hurry, hold my hands, and lastly, just one thing...
溺れるくらい愛してよ
Love me so much I drown in it!
全然私に興味ないじゃん 君が好きなのは自分でしょう
You're not interested in me at all, are you? The one you love is yourself!
やっぱり私に興味ないじゃん その話もう聞き飽きたわ
As I thought, you're not interested in me at all. I'm sick of hearing that story!
そもそも大体私に興味ないじゃん そうやってまたごまかして
In the first place, you're just not into me, covering it up like that again!
Get the last chance 覚悟はできてるの？
Get the last chance, are you prepared?
気まぐれメルシィ
Whimsical Mercy
お願い言わせて
Please, let me say it!
お前の苦労をずっと見ていたぞ
I've been watching your hard work all this time.
本当によく頑張ったな
You really worked hard.
ついに我慢が報われ 膨大な富を得る
Finally, your patience pays off and you will gain immense wealth.
このライブを飛ばしてしまえば これまでの苦労はすべて水の泡だ
If you skip this live stream, all your hard work so far will be in vain.
世界中がお前を否定しても 吾輩だけはお前を認めてやる
Even if the whole world denies you, I alone will acknowledge you.
散々苦しんだのだ もう楽になれ
You've suffered so much. Just ease your mind now.
富を望んでいるのなら やることがある
If you desire wealth, there is something you must do.
このライブを最後まで見て チャンネルを登録するんだ
Watch this live stream to the end and subscribe to the channel.
やり方は簡単だ 誰にでもできる
The method is simple. Anyone can do it.
下の赤いチャンネル登録ボタンを押して 高評価ボタンを押すのだ
Press the red subscribe button below and click the like button.
これで幸福の精算が始まる
With this, the payout of happiness begins.
吾輩は決して無理強いはしない
I will never force you.
やるもやらぬもお前次第だ
Whether you do it or not is up to you.
では締めくくりに吾輩の波動を送る
Now, in closing, I shall send you my wave energy.
吾輩の波動を送る 3 2 1
Sending my wave energy... 3, 2, 1...
今だ！
Now!
お前のライブ運は上昇している
Your live stream fortune is rising!
このままライブを見続けるのだ
Keep watching this live stream just like this!
喰ライ / 作詞・作曲・編曲：かいりきベア
[Song: Kurai / Music & Lyrics: Kairiki Bear]
甘い夢見て 心まで ラッラップラップ 餌付けて
Dreaming sweet dreams, feeding my heart with la-la-plump...
ただ深い微睡の奴隷 ラッラップラップ 混ざり合って くるくるる
Just a slave to deep slumber, la-la-plump mixing together, spinning round...
ひとつふたつと宵闇 ラッラップラップ 溶けてった
One, two, into the twilight, la-la-plump melted away...
ただ熱いその生命さえ ラッラップラップ 呑まれてさ くるくるくるる
Even that hot life itself, swallowed by la-la-plump, spinning round...
Me, you, for you, Be a, you, for, 前世前世の...
Me, you, for you, be a, you, for... from past lives, past lives...
ろコロコ その満たさげ
Ro-ko-ro-ko, with that unfulfilled look,
闇通わせ
bringing dark emotions into play,
まわりまわる世界
the world spins around and around.
この手に Hello, yes, My dark & black zone
In my hands—Hello, yes, My dark & black zone.
刮目 暗黒 悪 悪
Pay attention! Darkness, evil, evil,
Hello, yes, My dark & black zone
明日から見せる毒
The poison I'll show starting tomorrow,
ぐるぐる抱きしめて 毒毒
wrap around and embrace it, poison, poison.
ぐるぐる溜めさせて 毒毒
Let it build up round and round, poison, poison.
甘い夢見て 常闇のラップラップ 焼き付けて
Dream a sweet dream, burn in the rap of deep darkness.
そばで笑いかける 悪魔の声が鳴り響いて
Smiling right beside you, the demon's voice resounds.
ぐるぐる UFO, B-UFO, Follow Follow 絡めとられて I photo, Be UFO
Round and round UFO, B-UFO, follow, follow, caught up in it, I photo, Be UFO.
ろコロコ その日々さえ 闇通わせ
Ro-ko-ro-ko, even those days, filled with darkness,
黒く黒く染め上げて
dyed pitch black,
やがて混ざる世界
a world eventually blending together.
主観 一才 毒 毒 毒
Subjectivity, everything—poison, poison, poison.
溶け込み 満たして黒く
Melting in, filling up in black,
絶対でしょ 毒 毒
absolutely, right? Poison, poison.
ハーモニー交わる 世界一帯 毒 毒 毒
Harmonies intertwine, poison across the whole world.
刮目 暗黒 悪 悪
Pay attention! Darkness, evil, evil,
絶対でしょ 毒 毒
absolutely, right? Poison, poison.
あー見せて
Ah, show me!
ぐるぐる抱きしめて 毒 毒
Wrap around and embrace it, poison, poison.
ぐるぐる溜めさせて 毒 毒
Let it build up round and round, poison, poison.
テレスコープごしの感情
Feelings seen through a telescope,
ロッカーに全部詰め込んだ
I stuffed them all into a locker.
踊ってない夜を知らない
I don't know a night without dancing,
踊ってない夜が気に入らない
I can't stand a night without dancing!
踊ってない夜を知らない
I don't know a night without dancing,
踊ってない夜が気に入らないよ
I can't stand a night without dancing!
気に入らない夜なんて もう僕は知らない
I don't know any night I don't like anymore.
見えるこの目の涙 命の色に滲んでいる
The tears visible in these eyes bleed with the color of life.
何をノコして与えた
What did I leave behind and give?
問いかけて潰れてく
Asking questions, I crush down.
青と赤と白 混ざるこの世の中で叫んでいる
Blue, red, and white mix together in this world where I scream.
何を求めて歩いた
What was I seeking as I walked?
追いかけて疲れて
Chasing after it, I grew tired.
どのくらい 異常？
How abnormal am I?
壊れているの？
Am I broken?
壊れているよ
Yes, I am broken.
それでも息をしたい したい
Even so, I want to breathe, I want to...
君に見えてるなら
If you can see me,
夢のように最後の
like a dream, my final...
言葉も詰まるよ Error
words get choked up too... Error.
遠い日の言葉 淡い光が空に溢れている
Words from distant days, faint light overflows in the sky.
何を選んで並べた
What did I choose and line up?
涙色 重ねて
Layering teardrop colors...
浮かぶその体 意識の中 溶けて滲んでしまう
That floating body melts and bleeds inside my consciousness.
何を見つけて比べて
What did I find and compare?
悲しくて 忘れて
It's so sad, so forget it...
どのくらい 異常？
How abnormal am I?
歪んでいるの？
Am I distorted?
歪んでいるよ
Yes, I am distorted.
それでも息をしたい したい
Even so, I want to breathe, I want to...
夢を見ているの
Am I dreaming?
重なる愛に最後の
In this overlapping love, my final...
言葉も詰まるよ Error
words get choked up too... Error.
与えることも
I cannot give,
失うことも
nor lose,
忘れることも
nor even forget
できないの
anything...
暴れ出すこの
This raging
エラー
error,
殺して笑う僕がまた
killing and laughing, I am once again
エラー
an error...
壊していくの？
Are you destroying it?
壊して知るの？
Do you learn by destroying?
それでも涙 痛い
Even so, my tears hurt...
痛い
It hurts...
君に届いたの？
Did it reach you?
歌う声に愛はあるの？
Is there love in my singing voice?
言葉並べても
Even if I line up words,
重なる色 にじんで
overlapping colors bleed into each other...
壊れているの？
Is it broken?
壊れているよ
It is broken.
それでも息をしたい したい
Even so, I want to breathe... I want to...
君に見えてたの？
Could you see it?
夢のように彩るの
Like a dream, coloring everything...
言葉詰まるよ
My words choke up,
エラー
ERROR.
本日は
Today,
皆様、ラプラス・ダークネス生誕祭をご覧いただきありがとうございます。
thank you all for watching Laplus Darknesss's Birthday Celebration.
今回ホロライブのゲストと一緒に歌っていないことについて一言...
Regarding not singing together with Hololive guests this time, a word...
うあああ〜！
Waaaaah!
皆さんには分からないでしょうね！
None of you would understand!
このホロライブを！合体！させたい！
I wanted to unite Hololive like this!
どうしても！次の曲ゲスト呼びたくて！
I really wanted to invite guests for the next song!
いろんな人を呼びたいって声をかけていただいたら、ゲストの人数とかすごいことになって！
But when I reached out wanting to invite everyone, the guest list blew up!
他のゲストが呼べなくなったんですー！
So I couldn't invite any other guests!
うあああ〜！
Waaaaah!
というわけで、次の曲のゲストすごいです！
So anyways, the guests for the next song are incredible!
超天変地異みたいな狂騒にも慣れて
Getting used to the uproar like a super catastrophe,
こんな日常を平和と見間違う
mistaking such days for peace.
rambling coaster 揺さぶられながら
Rambling coaster, while being shaken,
見失えないものは何だ？
what is it that we cannot lose sight of?
平等性原理主義の概念に飲まれて
Swallowed by the concept of equality fundamentalism,
心までもがまるでエトセトラ
even our hearts become just an et cetera.
大嫌い
I hate it,
大好き
I love it.
ちゃんと喋らなきゃ 人形とさして変わらないし
If you don't speak properly, you're no different from a doll.
宵街を行く人だかりは
The crowds walking through the night streets
嬉しそうだったり
look happy,
寂しそうだったり
or look lonely.
コントラストが五線譜を飛び回り
The contrast flies around the musical staff,
歌とリズムになる
becoming song and rhythm.
ママレード＆シュガーソング、ピーナッツ＆ビターステップ
Marmalade & sugar song, peanuts & bitter step.
甘くて苦くて目が回りそうです
It's sweet and bitter, making my head spin.
南南西を目指してパーティを続けよう
Aiming south-southwest, let's keep the party going
世界中を驚かせてしまう夜になる
into a night that will amaze the whole world.
I feel 上々 連鎖になってリフレクト
I feel great, forming a chain and reflecting!
蓋世仙人？ 功利主義の勢力に揉まれて
Pushed around by world-class sages and utilitarianism,
僕らの音楽は道具になりさがる？
will our music degenerate into just a tool?
こちらを向いてよ
Look over here,
背を向けないでよ
don't turn your back,
それは正義の証明にならないけれど
though that won't prove righteousness...
祭囃子のあとで
After the festival music fades,
高ぶったままの人
some people stay excited,
泣き出し始めてしまう人
while others suddenly burst into tears.
多分同じだろう
They're probably the same deep down.
でも言葉にしようものなら
But if you try to put it into words,
稚拙が極まれり
it just sounds completely childish.
最高だってシュガーソング
"It's the best!" says the sugar song,
幸せってビターステップ
"This is happiness," says the bitter step.
死ねない理由をそこに映し出せ
Reflect the reason you can't die right there.
惜しかったって等速で明日は来ちゃうけど
Even if you regret it, tomorrow comes at a steady speed,
脳内天気予報のアップデートを果たしたなら
so update your internal weather forecast!
someday 狂騒が息を潜めても
Someday, even if the frenzy quiets down,
someday 正論に意味がなくなっても
someday, even if sound logic loses its meaning,
feeling song & step 鳴らし続けることだけが
just continuing to sound the feeling song & step
僕たちを僕たちたらしめる証明になる Q.E.D.！
is the proof that makes us who we are—Q.E.D.!
ママレード＆シュガーソング ピーナッツ＆ビターステップ
Marmalade & sugar song, peanuts & bitter step,
生きてく理由をそこに映し出せ
reflect your reason to live right there.
北北東は後方へ その距離が誇らしい
North-Northeast lies behind; that distance is something to be proud of.
世界中を 驚かせ続けよう
Let's keep surprising the entire world!
ママレード＆シュガーソング ピーナッツ＆ビターステップ
Marmalade & sugar song, peanuts & bitter step,
甘くて苦くて目が回りそうです
it's sweet and bitter, making my head spin.
南南西を目指してパーティを続けよう
Head South-Southwest and keep the party going;
世界中を驚かせてしまう夜になる
it'll be a night that astounds the whole world.
I feel 上々 連鎖になってリフレクション
I feel great, causing a chain reaction of reflections,
goes on 一興去って一難去ってまた一興
goes on, moving from one fun moment to a trouble, and on to fun again.
You got the happiness, taste the melody
え、ラプラス・ダークネスってオリ曲3曲しかないの？
Wait, Laplus Darkness only has three original songs?
やっぱ、期待しちゃダメじゃない 新曲なんて出すわけないんだから
I knew I shouldn't expect anything. There's no way she's releasing a new song.
ラプラス・ダークネスなんて当てにしちゃダメよ
You can't rely on Laplus Darkness, you know.
え、新曲出るの？ しかも DECO*27 さんなの！？
Huh, a new song is coming out? And it's by DECO*27?!
タイトル？
The title?
「バグラブ」？
"Bug Love"?
それって・・・つまり自己防衛？
Does that mean... self-defense?
この後披露するの？
She's going to perform it after this?
見ないとダメじゃない？
Then I have to watch it, right?
この後見逃しちゃダメよ
You shouldn't miss what's coming next.
つまり 自己防衛？
In other words... self-defense?
やっぱりラブレスハッピーじゃん
See, being loveless is being happy, after all!
あーまさか これってまさか
Ah, no way! Could this be...
好きってやつか どんなんか知らんけど
...that thing called love? I don't even know what it is,
は？ってなって火花バチってなるの 鈍感でいられたらなぁ
but I'm like 'Huh?' as sparks fly! I wish I could stay dense...
あーこんなはずじゃ とんだ恥じゃん 残念の始まりじゃん
Ah, this wasn't supposed to happen! How embarrassing, a disastrous start!
あーとんでも事案 ハートの治安 曖昧でおしまいじゃん
Ah, what an outrageous incident! My heart's peace of mind is ruined by ambiguity!
Down down 気になって気にしないとこ気になるとか
Down, down... Caring about things I shouldn't care about,
Down down 気まずくて気病む気じゃない
Down, down... It's awkward, but I don't feel like sulking.
バグってるラブ あたしなんですか？
Love is glitching out! Is this really me?
ヤダよガッカリラブデビューベイビーじゃん
No way! A disappointing love debut—I'm such a baby!
痛むだけの気持ち 最悪の見込み
Just painful feelings and the worst expectations,
好きって認めないね
I won't admit that I love you!
バグってるラブ あたしなんかじゃない
Love is glitching out! This isn't like me at all!
そうだやっぱりラブレスハッピーじゃん
That's right, being loveless is happy after all!
期待なんてなしな
Don't have any expectations!
あっじけバリア
Boring barrier!
好きってならないでね、の
Don't go falling in love, okay?
距離感です
That's my distance.
正直あたしは終わった
Honestly, I'm completely done for.
何しようがどうもモヤモヤが消えない
No matter what I do, this lingering feeling won't go away.
茫然ただ笑った
Stunned, I just laughed.
いつも通りロンリー 息をしたいのみ
Lonely as usual, I just want to breathe.
もう嫌
I hate this!
意地張っていじけるとかいじらしいから
Being stubborn, sulking, it's so pitiful...
恋路って冗談じゃない？
Isn't romance a total joke?
Ah...
バグってるラブ あたしなんです
Bugged love, that's what I am
やだよ がっかりラブ デビュー ベビーちゃん
No way, a disappointing love debut, baby
未体験の if に
To an unexperienced "if"
解釈 プレ気味
Slightly premade interpretation
好きっ て 好きじゃないわ
Saying "I like you"... I don't like you!
バグってるラブ あたしなんかじゃない
Bugged love, it can't be someone like me
そうだ やっぱりラブレス ハッピーじゃん
That's right, after all, loveless is happy
意外すぎる味が
An unexpectedly surprising taste
飲み込めないや
I can't swallow it
好きってまずいんだね
"Liking" tastes terrible, doesn't it?
こうやって枯れてくことが
If withering away like this...
思いの反動なら
...is the backlash of my feelings...
はじめから言って 知っときたいじゃん
Tell me from the start, I wanted to know!
それってちょっと卑怯じゃん
Isn't that a little unfair?
きみのことを気にする事も回避できたかもじゃん
I might have been able to avoid caring about you!
バグってるラブ あたしなんです
Bugged love, that's what I am
やだよ がっかりラブ デビュー ベビーちゃん
No way, a disappointing love debut, baby
痛いだけの気持ち
Feelings that are just painful
最悪の飲み込み
Swallowing the worst of it
好きって認めないね
I won't admit that I "like" you
バグってるラブ あたしなんかじゃない
Bugged love, it can't be someone like me
そうだ やっぱりラブレス ハッピーじゃん
That's right, after all, loveless is happy
期待なんてなしな
No expectations at all
あっけバリア
Abrupt barrier
好きってならないでね の距離感で
At a distance of "don't fall in love"
気になって気にしないと気なるから
Because if I care and try not to care, I end up caring...
いつだって逃げられるようなそんな距離感で
At a distance where I can escape at any time
やっぱりラブレス ハッピーじゃん
After all, loveless is happy!
というわけで なんとオリジナル曲が出るよー！
So, believe it or not, a new original song is coming out!
あと ジゴ坊おじさんが言ってた通り DECO*27さんが作ってくれたよー！ ありがとうね！
Also, like Jigobo-ojisan said, DECO*27 made it for me! Thank you!
「ヘリスケ」もオリジナルなんだけど どうでしたか？
"Helisuke" is an original song too, how did you like it?
できたね 1年で1曲ずつ作っていきたかったんだけど... あ！
We made it! I wanted to release one song every year, but... ah!
「Cry」はタイアップ曲だからノーカンで！
"Cry" was a tie-up song, so that doesn't count!
あれはね でもね 思ったより人気だったから...
That one, well, it turned out to be more popular than I expected, so...
今回 みんながこうやって見れるライブで初めて披露したよ！
...I performed it for the first time live in front of everyone today!
ライブでやるのは2回目！ 2回目だよ！
It's my second time performing it live! Second time!
えっとね 「バグラブ」はMVも公開するから絶対見てね！
Um, we're releasing an MV for "Bug Love" too, so definitely watch it!
そして 今年は... もしよかったら...
And this year... if you like...
というわけで この後はあれですよね グッズ情報ですよね！
Anyway, next up is the merch info, right?!
なんと 今回はCMがあるよー！ どうぞ！
Believe it or not, we have a commercial this time! Check it out!
誕生日記念 2025
[Title: Birthday Celebration 2025]
これどんな感じだ？
What's this like?
喋ったー！！
It talked!!
え？ 喋っ... え？
Huh? It talk... huh?
喋ったー！！
It talked!!
生誕祭記念ボイスキーホルダー！
[Title: Birthday Celebration Voice Keychain!]
ラプラスさんのグッズで 今回Tシャツが出るそうなんですが
Regarding Laplus's merchandise, I heard a T-shirt is coming out...
まことに遺憾です。 残念です。
It is truly regrettable. Quite disappointing.
いいTシャツ着てんじゃんかよ。 ぷるるだろ、それ。
You're wearing a great T-shirt right now. Isn't that Pururu?
バキバキラブ様です。
It's Baki Baki Laplus-sama.
ぐんぴぃはー
Gunpi-ha...
ラプラスさんの生誕グッズが カラスのニット帽らしいんですが
Apparently Laplus's birthday merch includes a crow beanie...
世界的なアイドルですもんね。 乗るしかない このビッグウェーブに。
Well, she's a world-famous idol. I have no choice but to ride this big wave.
はい CMでしたー！
Alright, that was the commercial!
どうだった？
How was it?
え？ よく分からない？
Huh? You didn't really get it?
しょうがないなー もう！ じゃあ 詳細を見せてあげましょう！ こちら！
Gosh, fine! Then let me show you the details! Right here!
ジャン！ 「ラプラス・ダークネス 誕生日記念2025」 フルセットはこちらです！
Ta-da! Here is the "Laplus Darknesss Birthday Celebration 2025" full set!
それでは 1つずつ内容を見ていきましょう！
Now then, let's take a look at each item!
まずはこちら！
First off, this one!
ジャン！ 「なんだよ これが！」 ということでね
Ta-da! With "What is this?!" on it,
イラストが入ったTシャツだよーん！
it's a T-shirt featuring an illustration!
このね イラストはね ちょぼらうにょぽみ先生が描いてくれたよ！ 言えたー！
This illustration was drawn by Choboraunyopomi-sensei! I said it!
可愛いでしょう！ いっぱい着てね！
Isn't it cute? Wear it a lot!
服はね何枚あっても困りませんからね、いっぱい着てください。
You can never have too many clothes, so please wear them a lot!
そして続いてはこちら！
And next up is this!
じゃん！
Ta-da!
ボイスキーホルダー私服衣装Ver.！
Voice Keyholder Casual Outfit Ver.!
ということでね 去年も思ったよりめちゃくちゃ大人気だった我が輩のボイスキーホルダーで
So, my voice keyholder from last year was way more popular than expected,
みんな「また売って！また売って！」って言われたから
and since everyone kept asking, "Please sell it again! Sell it again!"...
「えー、しょうがないなー」と思って また出すことにしました。
I thought, "Well, I guess I have no choice," and decided to release it again.
イラスト... イラストは...
The illustration... The illustration is...
イラストは今回もしろこ先生に描いてもらったよ！
The illustration was drawn by Shiroko-sensei again!
マジで可愛い！
It's super cute!
はい、どんなボイスが入ってるかお楽しみに！
Look forward to seeing what kind of voices are inside!
お次はこちら！
Next is this!
カラスニット帽！
Crow Beanie!
ということでね 我が輩にいつもつきまとってるカラスの...
So, themed after the crow that always accompanies me...
モチーフが入った... 顔か！顔が入ったニット帽です！
it has the motif... wait, face! A beanie featuring its face!
はい これ目出し帽になるんですけど...
Now, this can actually turn into a balaclava...
ここ目だけ見えてるやつ。
where only your eyes are showing right here.
これ ちょっとイベントとかにつけていくと...
If you wear this to an event or something...
防犯上危険なんで...
it might be a security risk...
イベントに行く時は顔出しで
so when going to events, keep your face exposed,
家で着ける時はこの目出し帽で着けてね！
and when wearing it at home, wear it as a balaclava!
温かいよ！
It's really warm!
そしてフルセット購入特典はこちら！
And the full set purchase bonus is this!
直筆メッセージ＆
Handwritten message &...
箔押し複製サイン入りちょぼらうにょぽみ先生の描き下ろしポストカード！
foil-stamped replicated signature postcard illustrated by Choboraunyopomi-sensei!
です！
That's it!
なんと今回は数量限定じゃないで〜す！
And surprisingly, this time it's not limited quantity!
頑張っていっぱい書きます！
I'll work hard and write a ton!
さようなら我が輩のお手々...
Goodbye, my hand...
そして、さらにフルセットを購入した方には
And furthermore, for those who purchase the full set,
hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAMEで使用できるカードが1枚ついてくるよ！
you'll get 1 card that can be used in the hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME!
じゃん！
Ta-da!
同封するカードはhololive production OFFICIAL SHOPで購入されたお客様のみ対象となります。
The enclosed card is only for customers purchasing at the hololive production OFFICIAL SHOP.
えっとね 特典につくのは
Um, what comes as the bonus is...
ゲームで1枚だけ使用できて 推しホロメンをアピールできるキーカード 推しホロメンカードです！
an Oshi-Holomen Key Card that lets you highlight your favorite Holomen in the game!
はい カードの詳細とか遊び方についてはhololive OFFICIAL CARD GAMEの公式ホームページで確認してください。
For details and rules, please check the official homepage of the hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME.
このカードは日本語版のみとなりますのでご了承ください。
Please note that this card is only available in Japanese.
そして我が輩がいる
And the booster pack containing me...
「キュリオスユニバース」も6月20日、来月！発売されるので一緒に使ってね！
"Curious Universe" comes out on June 20th next month! Use it together!
はい！ということでグッズもよろしく！
Alright! So please check out the merch!
ふぅー、今回はね...
Phew, this time...
ゲストが盛り沢山だったね！
there were so many guests!
えっと いろんな振り返りとかはまた配信で話すかもしれないから
Um, I might talk more about recaps and memories on a stream...
その時お楽しみに！
so look forward to that!
バイバーイ！バイバイバーイ！
Bye-bye! Bye-bye-bye!
インターネットでありがとう
[On-Screen Text: Thank you for the Internet]